Winnie
Winnie
It's so late.
怎么这么晚
Mrs. Lam, I feel like I'm being followed.
林太太，好像有人跟着我
Don't be silly
不是吧
My hubby is waiting for me, some way ahead. Don't worry.
我老公在前面等我，不用怕
You are scaring yourself.
是你自己吓自己
Anyway, you'd better find a day time job.
你呀，找一份日班的工作
It is not a place to walk in late at night by yourself.
每晚半夜三更一个女孩子放工不是太好
T oilet.
厕所
He needs to go to toilet.
上厕所
Have a shit or a piss?
大便还是小便
What's the difference? I need to go now.
大便小便都要去
Is he Mr. Suen?
好像是孙哥哥
Piss.
拉吧
I'm done. Don't keep staring, idiot.
走吧，看女孩看得呆着
Are you Mr. Suen?
请问你是不是孙哥哥
Bingo! I am right.
我没说错
Haven't seen you hosted the Police Voice show for a long time?
最近没看见你做警讯节目
I quitted that show for years.
我没做很多年了
Look at him, he looks much handsome than he was on TV.
你看他，真人比上镜俊多了
You are a real cop, right?
你真的是警察
Stupid! Every host in that show is a real cop.
你太笨了，所有做警讯的都是真警察
Really?
是吗
Mr. Suen.
孙哥哥
Yes, he is with me, we'll back to the station in 1 5 minutes.
是，到了，十五分钟后到警局
I am hungry; buy me a bowl of wonton noodles.
肚子饿，开车送我去吃碗云吞面
Okay.
好的
You can have whatever you want after the case finishes.
做完这案件什么都让你吃
But not now.
现在没得吃
Wonton noodles?
云吞面
Give you shits.
粪便就有你吃
Move! Don't stop!
开快点！不要停！
Don't come back
不要回来
I am sorry, Barrister T o.
不好意思，杜律师
Never mind.
不要紧
We still don't know
因为我们还没知道
whether Hung has got any key documents.
洪志文手上有没有关键文件
So, I would like to keep my original thought.
所以我想保留原来的想法
We shall focus on attacking the credibility of Hung,
集中火力攻击洪志文
the witness, your former accountant.
做污点证人的可信性
Five years ago he worked in the FTC
他五年前在美国联邦贸易委员会工作
At that time, he was strenuously censured by the SFC.
当时证监会有强烈的指摘
He was being accused of complicity with clients, cooking the books.
他串谋客户夸大业绩、造假账
Now I just want to know, my former accountant testify against me.
我只想知道，现在我的会计师指证我
Can I not go to the Court?
我是否一定要上庭？
And, even if I can get off, it will take me at least a year or so, right?
还有就算没事，也要搞上一年半载
When can I get back my frozen money?
我的资产何时才能解冻？
Mr. Yiu, there is an urgent parcel for you.
饶先生，有份急件送来给你
Open it. Y es, sir.
拆开它 知道
Mr. Yiu.
饶先生
This pillow is specially designed by my therapist for me.
这枕头是我的脊椎师特意给我订制
Nothing is better to have a good sleep, right?
做人最重要是睡得好，对吗
Ask Chuen to wait for me downstairs in 1 5 minutes.
叫阿全15分钟后在楼下等我
Yes, sir. Sit.
知道了，饶先生 坐吧
Don't you worry can't sleep well?
你怕不怕睡得不好
No. I have managed on a few hours' sleep since I was a kid.
不怕，我从小到大都睡得很少
Well. The lesser you sleep, the smarter you are.
是吗？睡得越少的人越聪明
I heard that Einstein slept for only two hours a day,
听说爱因斯坦每晚只睡两个小时
same as my son.
我的儿子也是
He fools around till dawn.
每天都玩到天亮才回来睡觉
After a few hours' sleep, he gets up for singing and dancing practices, or meeting the press.
睡没多久就练歌、练舞、见记者
See, he had dark circles under his eyes when he took this picture.
你看这照片拍的时候他有很大的黑眼圈
He looks great after the CG.
电脑矫正过而已
His new album will be released next week.
他的新唱片下个星期就发售
I'll ask Judy to send you one.
我叫J日dy送一张给你
Thanks.
谢谢
This morning, at 3:20 am,
今天零晨三时二十分
the witness Hung Chi-man, who involved in a money laundering case
一名涉嫌洗黑钱活动的污点证人洪志文
was shot to death while he was being extradited from Canada.
从加拿大引渡回香港途中，中枪身亡
Can you explain how did the murderer know which flight you were on?
请解释凶手怎能预知你们乘哪航班回来
Maybe someone in Canada leaked it out.
加拿大那边可能有人走漏了消息
Or they could get the information from the airline network.
也有可能是骇入航空公司网络里查到
What they need is just to know my name.
只要知道我的名字就可以
Apart from your subordinates,
除了你的下属外
does anyone else know you took that flight?
还有谁知道你乘这航班回来
I've told you,
我不是刚说过
I never told anyone.
我没有告诉过任何人
You are interrogating me, am I a suspect now?
你绕圈子不停的问，把我当作疑犯吗？
I haven't bathed yet.
我还没洗澡
You're also a cop.
你也是警察
When you take a statement from a witness, you will do the same.
你审问证人时也会套取他的记忆
The witness now wants to piss.
证人要求上厕所
Okay.
好的
Has the finger-print report come yet?
指纹报告出了没有
Not yet or no findings?
报告没出来还是验不出指纹
No finger prints.
验不出指纹
They are experts.
他们是高手
If you can get their finger prints, they are not experts.
能让你们验出来就不是高手
Why did you cut my line?
为什么挂我的电话
Damn you!
你真是的
have you found out the source of the gun?
怎么样，查到那枪的来源没有
What the hell are you doing?
你做什么？
Police!
警察！
Show me your warrant!
有没有拘捕令！
You are a cop, you should know the rules.
你是警察应该知道规矩
I am To Hou-sang, Mr. Yiu's attorney.
我是饶先生的律师，杜厚生
Think twice before taking every step.
每做一件事之前，想清楚比较好
Boss Jim is on the line.
詹先生找你
Any good news?
有什么好消息？
It's almost done. Give me a few more days.
差不多了，多给我几天的时间
A few more days. How many exactly?
几天，多少天？
It's really almost done. I am very concerned about it.
事情还没解决，我比你还紧张
Really! I don't think so.
你紧张？不是吧
I saw you on the entertainment pages yesterday.
我昨天看娱乐版，看到你出镜
Hugging your son, you looked so happy.
儿子笑得合不拢嘴
Don't read the entertainment pages, read the front page tomorrow.
明天不用看娱乐版了，看港闻版
You shall be happier.
你会更开心
I can't quit. I enjoy reading the entertainment pages everyday.
不看怎么行？我每天都看娱乐版
I am your son's big fan.
我是你儿子的歌迷
I follow him everyday.
我跟随着他
Where does he go, what pills does he take...
他每天到哪里，吃什么药丸
I know everything well.
我全都清清楚楚
Better than the paparazzi.
比狗仔队更厉害
My son's songs don't suit you.
我儿子的歌不适合你
I promise, sure everything will be okay.
我答应过你，肯定可以办妥
I get stuck in heavy traffic. I don't want it.
道路挤塞，我也不想
Damn your traffic! Make a U-turn then.
挤什么挤，塞车就掉头
Now the witness is dead,
现在污点证人己经死了
this case has been handed over to the Serious Crime Bureau.
这案件已经交给了重案组
Who killed him or who leaked out the information?
是谁杀了他，又是谁走漏风声
Now leave it to the Serious Crimes Bureau.
就让重案组去查好了
You guys are not green. You should know
你们不是第一天当警察
Hung Chi-man is now dead.
洪志文一死
All the evidences produced by him were gone, useless.
他交出来的几份影印文件就没用
On the other hand, this case is at an dead end.
换句话说，这件案有头没尾到此为止
Yiu Tin-chung has applied to the court to release his frozen assets.
饶天颂已经向法院申请解冻他的资产
I believe that it still take some time for the judge to proceed the release.
我相信法官没这么快同意
But it won't take long.
不过也拖不了多久
Now, Jim Pak-tat is our only lead.
我们只剩下詹柏达这条线
Chu, debrief us.
小朱，说说情况
Sir, I have followed Jim's file from the very beginning.
长官，詹柏达一向是由我跟进的
He carries diplomatic visa.
他拿外交护照出入境
Their embassy knows we are investigating him.
他们的领事知道我们正调查他
He filed several complaints against us with the Security Bureau.
他到保安局投诉我们
Chu.
小朱
I don't want to hear the history.
我不想听多年前的旧资料
We have to make every damn effort to nail Yiu only for his money-laundering.
我们只要钉死饶天颂洗黑钱的事就行
I don't care about any other things.
其他的事不要理
Save face for the unit this time.
给人拦了一次糊已经很没面子
You'd better go home earlier to take some sleep.
你早点回去睡吧
Can't sleep? Well! Let's go karaoke.
不睡？去唱歌吧
Don't like it? How about dancing?
不唱歌？跳舞又怎样
No dancing, alright let's go dining then.
不跳舞就吃饭吧
No dining! Race me to the end of the road.
不吃饭！不如走一趟
Look at you, look like shits. Watch out! Don't back up!
一辈子都是这样，不要倒车，小心点！
Get out from the Admiralty station, and then take the bus 1 03.
在金钟站出来，然后坐103号巴士
Get off at Pokfield Road.
到蒲飞路下车
Walk straight for further five minutes.
走五分钟路就到了
Right, find Uncle Choi in the Missing Person Unit.
没错，跟着到失踪人口调查科找才叔
See you at the entrance.
在门口等
Don't forget to bring your bottle of herbal oil.
别忘了带一瓶驱风油
It's late, why do people still come to I. D. the body?
这么晚还有人来认尸
every mother must be hurried to know...
没办法，每个母亲都想看看
whether the one lying here is her missing son.
躺在那里的是不是自己的儿子
If you ask her to come tomorrow,
你要她明天才来
she can't help but wait for the dawn.
等于要她眼睁睁的看着天亮
If she proves it is not her son,
如果知道不是的
she could believe her son would live at least for one more day.
最少她觉得儿子能多活一天
Just like them, what makes you come this late?
你也好不了，多少这么晚还来找我
After a long-haul flight, I can't sleep.
坐完长途飞机，睡不着
It's ten years, what are you still waiting for?
十年了，还等什么
That's the point.
就是…
How can a person disappear for ten years without leaving any clues!
哪有人失踪了十年连尸体都没有
You are a cop!
你是个警察
Bruce Lee, where was he? Tell me.
黄德辉在那，你说
Your girl has no emigration records in these ten years.
你女朋友都没有出境
How big is Hong Kong? How come you still can't find her?
香港有多大…为什么找不到
Maybe, she had an accident.
可能遇上意外
Lost memory, doesn't know the way home!
失去记忆，不懂回家
will you shelter a stranger for ten years?
那有人收留人超过十年
Not even a cat or a dog.
猫狗都不会
Whenever I raise those possibilities you give me the same answer.
我每次提出这些可能性你总这样回答我
Such perfectly consistent statement surely you'll be a good witness.
口供那么一致，你做证人一定没问题
It is the fact.
这是事实
Admit it. You just don't want to face reality.
你这个人就是不接受现实
Buddy, how can you be a cop?
你怎么当警察，兄弟？
Doesn't the duty of a cop mean to find out the truth, doesn't it?
做警察不是要坚持查到水落石出
You'd better apply for a transfer to my unit.
不如你申请调来这里
I am getting retired two months later.
反正我还有两个月就退休
You're off soon?
你下班了
Very soon.
差不多了
Listen, your body clock stopped, change your battery.
不过你的钟停了，换电吧
Don't touch it!
不要动他！
It's a male, none of your business.
是男的，不适合你
I can hear she's calling me the whole day.
今天她好像在叫我
Don't say that outside this room.
这些话让我听到好了
If your boss hears that,
如果让你的上司听到
He would probably send you to the asylum. Idiot!
会调你去看守精神病院，痴线
What are you eating?
你吃什么？
What do you think?
在硷房还可以吃什么？
Spaghetti Marinara, for sure.
当然是干尸伊面
So pretty!
好漂亮
I wish the time would stop right at this moment.
如果时间可以永远停留在这一刻就好了
Stop!
停！
It stopped.
停了
You're always mine!
你永远都属于我！
Such dance scared the hell out of me!
睡着都给他吓醒！
Is that a rehearsal or not?
彩排还是正式？
They seem lack of practices.
舞步好像不一致
Whatever! Let's back to the work.
不要管别，干自己的工作
Do you see anyone from the Serious Crime Bureau?
不觉得有重案组的人
They may disguise themselves as the waiters.
或者他们早就在船上扮侍应生
Or, the fans. Push someone into the water!
说不定是那些歌迷，小心掉到海里！
I should have transferred to the Serious Crimes Bureau.
早知道这样，我早点调去重案组
Those are nicer jobs.
这些工作我都会做了
T o's wife
杜厚生太太
Amy
Amy
I should have asked for 20 percent more.
早知道多收两成
The buyer is a billionaire.
这买家的生意是上亿
It's finished. Don't mention it again.
做完的工作就不要再提
You don't need to know who paid you.
钱是谁给的你也不需要知道
I told you not to come back.
我早告诉你不要回来
You just don't listen to me.
不听话
Thinking of the money,
想着那些钱
I remember Lo taught me that, women and money,
阿捞教的，女人和钱
they forget you once you leave
一走就会变心
Didn't Lo tell you this?
阿捞有没有告诉你
He was once paid by fake money.
有一次他收到一包假钱
How dare it cheat a killer!
杀手都敢骗
Killer, so what?
杀手又怎样
That day in the airport,
那天在机场
just half second late,
如果，l曼了半秒
or half inch wide,
或者偏差了半时
I would have killed that cop.
那个警察随时会死掉
I know that cop.
我认识那个警察
He is Mr. Suen who anchored the Police Voice.
他是警讯里的孙哥哥
Does this matter to you?
这跟你有关系？
I knew his girlfriend.
我认识他的女朋友
Jump, jump
下去，下去
Hey, come down, too.
你也要下去
Let's play something else.
我们玩别的
What's up? Go to hell!
怎样？死了没有
Not so soon.
没事，我死不了
Hey, get some beer. Do you want to fool me?
喝啤酒 你是不是玩我
Yiu Ha! Where are you? Stop hiding! Come out.
饶夏，你去那里？不要，玩出来啦！
When did you last see your son?
你最后见你的儿子是什么时候
Last Sunday, he went home for dinner.
星期天，他回家吃饭
Are you living together?
你们是不是一块儿住？
He stayed in the yacht lately.
他最近多在游艇上过夜
Have you checked the yacht?
有没有试过去游艇上找他？
Sure.
当然有
Then, in the yacht,
那你找他的时候
did you notice anything wrong?
有没有发现游艇上有什么不对劲？
Let's say, any sign of fighting! Or is it messy?
有人打过架或乱七八糟
Have you called the record company?
有没有找过唱片公司？
Is he out of town for MV recording or promotion somewhat?
会不会是出外做宣传或拍MV
No.
没有
Did you receive any calls for ransom?
没有接过勒索电话？
Does anyone want to harm you?
那有没有人想对你不利
Commercial Crimes Bureau.
商业罪案调查科
Mr Yiu Ha has been missing over 48 hours.
饶夏先生失踪超过48小时
As the father, sure he is not in a good mood.
做爸爸的心情一定不会好
Hope you'd understand that.
希望大家可以谅解
Mr. Yiu, it is a matter of routine.
饶先生，这些是例行问题
The more information we get,
你多给我们资料
the faster we may find your son.
我们就能尽快帮你找回儿子
If you agree,
如果你同意
I'll arrange setting taps on all your phone lines.
我会安排同事监听你家所有的来电
It's most probably a kidnap.
因为绑票的机会相当大
Tapping... tapping my lines!
监听监听，监听我家的电话
Guess what! They tapped all my calls long ago.
他们早就在监听我家电话
Any news?
有没有消息
When can I get back my frozen money?
我的钱什么时候可以解冻
Be more patient, shall be within a week.
放心，再过十天八天
They shall have no further excuse.
他们没有藉口再拖
A week?
十天八天
I am running out of patience? And my son...
这十天八天我怎么过啊？我的儿子…
Are you saying that the missing of your son and this case are related?
你觉得两件事有关系吗？
They are putting pressure on me to return the money.
他们逼我交数
They may suspect me of embezzling the money, so they kidnap...
或者怀疑我私吞公款，所以捉…
Are you sure?
你肯定？
This is one of the possibilities.
这是其中一个可能性
They give me no damn answer.
他们没有回答
Maybe, that bastard son overdosed on his pills.
或者是那臭小子啃丸出事
Or, it is a real kidnapping.
又或者真是绑架勒索
Anyway, anything could happen.
总之什么可能性都会发生
Otherwise, I won't report it to the police.
要不然就不会报警
You have someone for doing dirty work, right.
你们有人调查
Yes, I get a private eye.
有，找私家侦探
I've tried my people on it.
我这边都查过了
Your guys have to be gentler; I don't want to screw them up.
你的人比较斯文，我不想把事情搞大
Understood.
好的
Yes, To hired me to find Yiu Ha, but...
杜厚生是请我找饶夏，不过…
you know, he is the big big lawyer.
人家是当红大律师
I can never meet him in person.
哪有空和我开会
I met only the small folks.
我见的都是他的下属
Sure, I am not the only one working for To.
而且律师楼也不只我一个人帮忙
Chan and Fat Kwan also take his jobs.
阿陈，肥关也有接工作做
Fine, do you find anything then? Who did it?
那你有没有查出什么，是谁干的？
Mister Suen, I'll speak to you if I can speak.
孙哥哥，很多事情不能说就是不能说
Buddy here, buddy there when you need my money or help.
找我借钱、套资料时就称兄道弟
Now you call me Mister.
现在就叫我孙哥哥
Just return your buddy a favor this time, okay?
你算是帮旧同事的忙
I might get killed for this.
这案件很容易出事的
Just can't tell.
不能说
I have to go.
我先走
By the way, tell you another lead.
说另一件事给你听
It's just hearsay. I take no responsibility.
反正都是听回来的，不用负责任
A girl called Ting, a new face.
听说有个女人叫何定姐
She is very active recently.
这两三年才冒起
She is an agent of assassins.
专门代客宰果子狸
All of them are pros.
又干净，保证没有后顾之忧
Have you told the Serious Crime Bureau?
那你有没有说给重案组知道？
You think I am a patron?
你认为我是善长仁翁吗？
Who is looking for Ting?
请问那一位找阿定？
Doctor Chan suggested me to order a health pillow from you.
陈医生介绍我来订购健康枕头
Wrong number.
你打错啦
This site contractor keeps a mistress.
地盘工头在东莞养了情妇
That woman broke his safe.
这女人撬开了他的抽屉
took all his stuff
拿走了所有的东西
Then mess up the place, make it look like being robbed.
然后再把现场搞得跟被劫杀过一样
That's so cheap.
太低级了
Turn him down.
推了他
You don't take this job, someone else does.
你不干有人干
Are you insane!
你疯啦！
Take such a job will
这种工作也接
Ruin our reputation
坏声誉呀
And you promise me that you work only for me.
还有你应承过我，只找我做
I don't remember that.
我不记得我答应过你什么
Indeed, I'll give it to someone else
而且我把这工作给别人做
and sleep with him.
再跟这个人上床
Thank you.
谢谢
All here.
就这么多
That's all we got.
他只给我们这几张
When will the photographer come back?
那个摄影师何时才回来
He is a free-lancer; he's not in this office.
他是个散工，有工作才回来
Our magazine can't afford to hire so many paparazzi.
我们杂志社哪能请这么多的狗仔队
Here are 20 something pictures.
这总共只有二十几张相片
Will there be more with him?
会不会还有些在他那处
Sure, you know he is a free-lancer.
肯定有，你也知道做摄影的
He must take as many as he can and sell to as many magazines as possible
照了一大堆，能多卖一间报社就多一间
You just can't do anything with them.
拿他们没有办法
Where can I find him?
我想找那个摄影师
Thomas
Thomas
Thomas Liu
Thomas Liu
I didn't kill that guy.
这家伙不是我杀的
Trust me, Mr. Suen.
你相信我，孙哥哥
You're tired.
你累了
Get away! Police! Stop!
走开，警察！不要跑
Take cover!
走呀
No!
不要呀！
No! Don't do that!
不要呀！不要呀
Stop, please!
不要玩啦！
I have something to tell you.
我有话跟你说
Shoot.
说呀
I am pregnant.
我有啦
My baby!
BB !
I've got a son! Junior Suen.
我有了小孙？我有了小孙
Then we'll have our baby welcoming party right after the wedding banquet
那不是摆完了喜酒再摆满月酒
Bravo!
太捧了！
I've got a son!
我有了小孙呀！
Wonderful! I've got a son! I am a father!
太捧了！我有小孙！
Fong! Fong!
素芳！素芳！
hang on! Don't sleep! Call an ambulance!
你撑住呀！不要睡！快叫救护车
here is Central Market.
总部！这里是中环街市
Calling backup, one officer down.
现场发生爆炸，有伤者，请支援
Seal off the area now!
马上封闭现场
Yes sir.
知道！
I didn't kill the photographer.
那摄影师不是我杀的
You know how much I charge for killing.
你知道我杀人多贵
I know, it is for fun, huh?
知道，只是玩玩吧
I'm a killer. I should do something out of charity occasionally.
做我们这行业，间中要做些善事
Hey, you want to beat me?
怎么，又想打我
Don't be so stubborn.
做人怎么要那么古板
If you are capable, sometimes you need not follow the rules.
有本事就不一定要守规矩
Look at them.
你看这些人
If I want to, I would have been one of them.
我愿意的话早就做了他们
Why did you make contact with that cop?
为什么你要碰那个警察
Why didn't you listen to me?
为什么你不听我的话？
You have gone too far.
你知道这样是玩过头
That something really stuck in my mind,
有些事放在心里很久
I just want to do it, and did it.
想做就去做
If I was that obedient, I wouldn't have been a killer.
这么听话我就不是杀手
1 5:00.
下午三点
There is a cargo ship to the Philippines.
有货船去菲律宾
Good, I can go diving.
也好，可以潜水
Look at you!
看看你这个样子
Your head's bleeding. Wounds on foot.
头也出血，脚也受伤
What the hell were you doing there?
你去那里干什么
I asked you to pin a tail on Yiu.
我叫你去跟饶天颂！
Stop!
站住！
You have the right to suspend me.
你有权把我停职
I also have my right to say that I am not wrong.
我也有权认为我没有做错
Money laundering, killing witness, the missing of the suspect's son.
洗黑钱、杀证人、疑犯的儿子失踪
All these might be connected.
一切都可能有关连
If you don't look into them, you'll never know.
不调查是永远都不会知道
Yes, your girl has been missing for 1 0 years.
是，你女朋友失踪十年了
Is that also connected here?
跟这事情会有关系吗？
Following orders
服从命令
obeying your commander, no private investigation.
听指挥统一行动
These are the basics for all the police.
每个警察都会做到
Except you.
除了你
Lucky you, the autopsy report stated that
幸好验尸报告上写着
the photographer died over 20 hours.
那个摄影师死了20多小时
And Chu can confirm your alibi.
又有小朱帮你做证
If not, someone must say that you are mad,
如果不是，别人说你不顺气
killed the son of the suspect, and was pictured by the paparazzi,
杀了疑犯的儿子，再被狗仔队照了相
and murdered the witness
说你杀人灭口
Do you think you can say you are not involved?
到时啥也洗不清？
Think about if you were me
换了你
the witness was shot dead right in front of you.
眼睁睁看着自己押的犯人给杀了
What would you do, sir?
你会怎样，长官？
You're trash!
你太差了！
Defendant, please stand up.
请被告起立
Now this court finds
本席宣布
on the charge of D. D. possession against Wong Man-kit
被告黄文杰…
verdict of not guilty
藏毒罪名不成立
and that he be acquitted accordingly.
无罪释放
Mr. To!
杜律师！
It's Mao Wai-ben.
牟伟彬呀！
Congratulations, can I talk to you for a few minutes?
恭喜，不介意麻烦你几分钟
You should contact John.
你不是一直找阿John联络
I know, but for this time, I think I should talk to you directly.
我知道，不过这案件应该直接找你谈谈
Have you found Yiu Ha?
你找到饶夏？
Take a look at these pictures first.
这里有几张相片，先看看吧
from bank tomorrow
银行那边
You'll get the notice of the release of your frozen money
最迟明天可以收到解冻信
Thank you.
谢谢
By the way, I have something to show you.
对了，有些东西想给你看
It's from my private eye.
是私家侦探给我的
Apart from Yiu Ha's yacht,
那天除了饶夏的船之外
there were eight other yachts on that day,
还有八艘船
According to the records of the pier,
根据码头纪录
That ship docked at 21 :00.
这艘船是那天九时靠过来了
and departed at 22:43.
十时四十三分离开
It's a leased ship.
这船是租回来
The leasing company didn't disclose the identity of the lessee.
租船公司拒绝说是谁租
Leave them to the police, they'll find out very soon.
交给警方调查，很快可以查出来
Mr. Yiu
饶先生
if you still can't find Yiu Ha after your money is released,
如果资产解冻后还没有饶夏的消息
do you still think that it was done by your Boss?
你还会怀疑是你那边的人做？
When my elder son was knocked down to death by a car,
上次大儿子被车撞死
at least I know what happened.
都不像现在这样
Please let me know whether my only son is alive or not.
是生是死都让我知道
I am not involved!
不关我事！
Hey, Baby.
女儿
Moca! Run!
Moca！快点！
1 2 3 up!
一二三起
Do you know Mao Wai-ben?
你认识牟伟彬？
We used to patrol together in Kwun Tong.
以前一起在观塘驻守
Do you know him well?
熟悉吗？
We go out for dinner every once in a while.
有时候会去喝茶
When did you last see him?
你最近见他是什么时候？
Last Wednesday.
上星期三
After quitting the force, he becomes a private detective.
他没干以后做了私家侦探
I have asked him for some information.
我找过他拿资料
What kind of information?
找什么资料
The case of Yiu's son.
饶天颂儿子的案件
What did he give you?
他给了你什么资料
Nothing.
没有
At the photographer's house, other than the suspect,
那天你在那摄影师家除了看到疑犯之外
did you see anyone else?
有没有见到其他人
Nope.
没有
Really!
还有呢
I know what would happen if I give a false statement.
我知道给假口供有什么结果
What happened to Mao?
老牟出了什么事
We found his body.
我们找到他的尸体
The photographer might have been killed by the same murderer.
摄影师可能是他干掉
The security guard of that building said that he saw Mao there the night before.
大厦看更说他前晚去过那儿
Mao ran into debt.
老牟欠了几笔钱…
The pictures of the photographer may turn his situation around.
摄影师的相可以帮他翻身
I think I can take over Mao's job.
看来我可以顶替老牟的工作
T ake it easy! (Pakistan)
不要伤心（巴基斯坦话）
Bye!
拜拜！
Bye! Take it easy!(Pakistan)
拜拜，不要伤心（巴基斯坦话）
You know Indian! I don't know you are so smart!
印度话也懂，这么聪明
That's Pakistan.
是巴基斯坦话
To work here, I have to learn more languages, even though just a bit.
做我们这工作什么话都要懂一点点
If the Head knows it, I'll be fired.
要是让重案组知道，连长棒都泡汤
I'll pay the rest of your living.
我供养你
I have all sorts of interest;
缥赌饮吹我什么都有兴趣
not even a millionaire can afford paying my living! You?
李嘉诚也养不起我，就你？
You're going to be fired.
你的警察职位都快被取消
You'd better mind your own ass.
先管自己吧
Look at you, smell like corpses.
看你，身体比尸体还臭
How many days that you haven't bathed?
几天没洗澡？
Would that make you take pity on me?
这样才能取得你的同情，是不是？
Mao was being strangled
老牟原本是被人勒死的
See the deep gash on his right neck.
右边脖子的血痕那么深
The murderer is a left-hander.
就是说凶手是左撇子
The gash is thin; it must be a wire again.
这痕这么小，一定又是钢线
Again?
又是？
A similar case happened last month.
上个月才有一宗
I don't know the wire is on sale,
最近不知是钢线大减价
or the left-handed killer is on sale.
还是左撇子杀手大减价
Left-hander again?
又是左撇子？
I went with a family to I. D. that body. It's a MP (Missing Person).
我陪那些家属一起认尸，是人口失踪
Give me that file.
借那份文件来看看
The body was found and the case was closed.
找到尸体，结了案
The papers must have been sent back.
文件肯定是拿回去了
Well, find Leung Tek at Shumshuipo Police station.
这样吧，你去深水涉警署找梁德
Tell him you're my friend.
说是我的朋友
Suen, don't blame me. I have to tell you again...
阿孙，不要说我恃老卖老
Uncle Choi, you know,
才叔，你知道
I just can't stop.
我不能停
If I stop, I'll... Back to ten years ago?
一停我就回去 回去十年前是吧？
Lately I saw a person.
最近我看到一个人
She looks utterly like Fong.
她和素芳有九成相似
So, go and pursue her. There's nothing worse than you are now.
那就去泡她吧，总比现在好
She is married, has kids, and is living in a big house.
人家有丈夫、有儿女，住大屋
She is blessed.
多幸福
Every time I see her house lighted.
每次我看她家里开了灯
I have an illusion that.
我都有一个错觉
Fong is waiting there for me to have dinner.
素芳在等我回家吃饭
Why don't you think of it this way?
不如这样想吧
Actually, Fong is still alive.
其实素芳还在
And you have broken up with her, okay?
不过分手，可以吗？
Okay, find Fong for me.
你找回素芳给我
Then I break up with her.
我和她分手
Suen, you don't need to find Leung Tek.
那你不用去找梁德
Go to find Chan at the funeral home.
你去九龙殡仪馆找阿陈
Cause you are a dead man.
因为你死定了
Two morning walkers found the death body in an alley at Nam Chong Street
两个晨运客在南昌街的小巷里发现尸体
The victim named So Fu-on, 28 years old.
死者叫苏富安，28岁
A staff in a convenient store nearby
附近便利店的伙计
witnessed that he bought something that night.
认出他在案发晚上来过买东西
But his two thousand dollars were still with him.
但他身上的二千块就没有失去
He wasn't a decent guy.
不过他也不是什么好人
He had two previous criminal convictions.
有过两次案底
Both are indecent assaults.
两次都是非礼
For the first time, he was sentenced to be bound over.
第一次判守行为
For the next time, he was sentenced to jail for half a year.
第二次就坐牢半年
Last year, he was charged with rape and murder.
去年控告他奸杀
Since there was only circumstantial evidence, he was not found guilty.
不过只有环境证供，所以不能把他定罪
The victim was only 1 3. Poor girl.
那受害女孩只有13岁，真惨
Would it be done by the victim's family?
会不会是女孩家人干？
I've checked, but I don't think so.
我查过了，不像啊
The murderer is quite a character, like using wires.
那么有个性，用钢线
Shouldn't it be easier to buy a sharp knife?
牛肉刀很容易买到
Maybe the killer is an obsessive hygiene addict.
说不定下手的人是有洁癖
With obsessive cleanliness, with a strong power,
有洁癖，力气大
and left handed.
而且是个左撇子
I, myself, haven't seen such a murderer before.
我梁德就没有见过了
You can't beat me to it.
你不够我快
Drive off!
开车吧！
I have something good for you.
我有好东西便宜你
These pictures were taken from the photographer's house.
这些相片在从摄影师家中拿走
I guess the photographer saw Yiu Ha brought the LSD,
我的推测是那摄影师想捕捉饶夏买药丸
They were so sneaky, so he took the pictures.
看到他鬼鬼祟祟，所以把他拍下来
Never miss a single opportunity.
宁杀错不放过
To Hou-sang sold pills to Yiu Ha?
杜厚生卖药丸给饶夏？
Does it look like that?
你说会不会？
You should ask what T o came for.
你应该问他来干什么
Only these two pictures?
这两张照片？
Not just two, there's many.
不只两张，还有很多
But those are useless to you.
不过那些对你没用
The one who killed the photographer took the CD-R away.
杀死摄影师的人拿走了光碟
But he forgot about the hard disk.
但是没有拿走硬盘
That guy is not familiar with computers.
这家伙不会电脑
How do I know if those pictures are not fake?
我怎么知道这些照片是不是你造出来
I don't know what you want.
我怎么知道你是什么居心
I also don't know what I want.
我也不知道自己有什么居心？
Why do I pick you, a suspended police among the force, for help?
千挑万选竟选一个被停职的警察来便宜
Maybe, I want to show you...
或者我想证明如果我当警察
If I were a cop, I would have been a better one.
一定比你好
Should you actually be a cop, you'd know that
你当过警察就会知道
it's much easier to be a criminal.
做贼多容易
You have rules to comply; sure you can't react at will.
你要守规矩，当然做什么都碰壁
Sometimes, the police should play the role of crooks.
有时候警察要假扮贼人
And the crooks should play the role of the police.
贼就换位置当警察
That would be fun.
这样才好玩
Many of your buddies welcome quick money.
你有很多同僚都会做兼职赚外快
Otherwise, no one would know which flight you took that day!
要不然怎会有人泄露风声
That made you meet your Waterloo at the airport.
害你在机场碰了一鼻子灰
Keep driving! Return it to me!
看前面 还我
If you don't want to die, keep driving!
不想死就看前面
Someone asked me to tell you.
有人拜托要我跟你说
Your girlfriend is dead.
你的女朋友已经死了
It was just an accident.
是意外
It was quick. No pain.
很快，没有什么痛苦
Mr. Jim.
詹先生
Any good news? Tell me.
有什么好消息？说给我听听
My son has been reported missing for fifteen days.
我的儿子已经失踪十五天
Isn't it for promotion?
搞宣传吧
Do you know where he is?
你会不会知道他在哪里
How can I know that?
我怎么会知道
Answer me.
你回答我一句
Is he with you?
他到底是不是在你那里？
Okay, I answer you now.
我现在回答你一句
My boss can't stand the waiting any longer.
我的老板已经忍无可忍
If you can't fix it,
如果你还是搞不好
not only your son disappeared,
别说你的儿子失踪
you and I would disappear too.
我和你也会失踪
Don't get me embroiled.
你不要把我连累
Let me heat some milk for you.
我煮些牛奶给你喝
You'll have better sleep then.
喝了会睡的更好
That's nothing, go back to sleep.
快点睡吧
If you change to handle civil cases,
不如改去做民事案件
you must have less trouble.
那便不用这么烦
That's easier said than done!
那有这么容易？说改便改
We just spend lesser and save it up.
赚少一点钱，省点用便行
We can sell this house and the other two apartments
我们卖了那两层楼，再卖掉这房子
I believe that we can pay off the loan.
我想应该足够还清这那笔帐
Where shall we live if we sell all our properties?
把房子都卖光我们一家人住在那里？
Rent a house, just like most of the people do.
租房子住，很多人都租房子住
No way!
不行！
I can't lose.
我不可以输
Lose some money, but you can earn a comfort life.
输了钱，最少赢回安乐！
I am comfort.
我很安乐
I used to be a light sleeper.
我从小到大都睡很少时间
Come on, go to sleep.
来吧，快点睡
Has Yiu got his money back?
饶天颂的钱解封没有？
Don't ask.
不要问
You need not know that.
这些事你不应该知道
Come on, go back to sleep.
快点睡吧，来
Hubby...
老公
Can you pick your own case next time?
你下次可以挑案件做吗？
I have no choice!
哪能挑
They all said they're innocent.
每个人都说自己是无辜
If there is one real innocent person in every ten cases,
如果十件案件里，其中一件真的是无辜
at least, I do one thing correct.
最少我做对了一件事
You hired someone to kill me!
找人杀我
And you asked such a shit to kill me!
还要找废物去干
Who do you think I am? You stupid ass!
你当我是什么呀 你这个笨蛋
Why do you come back? Why?
你回来干什么，你回来干什么
Don't you think you deserve to die?
你觉得自己不该死是吗
You should have died for 1 0 times already!
像你这种人早就该死十次八次
You deserve all that happened to you today, you know that?
今天的一切是你自己做成的你知道吗？
In this world, don't you think
你以为世界上
you're the only killer and I am the only agent, don't you?
只你一个杀手，只我一个经纪人
You, stupid! Damn you!
十条命都不够死
I just know buyers are all around the world.
我只知道这世界上最多的是买家
Call your buyer.
你回覆你的买家
Tell him I need 3 million to settle it.
尾数要多三百万才能摆平
Otherwise, ask him to read the newspaper tomorrow.
要不然有人随时回来将臭事都抖出来
Please bring my son back to me. Please guide me through this.
求你把儿子还给我，给我指引
Send me back my son
把儿子还给我
What do you want to eat? Wonton noodles?
你想吃什么？云吞面好吗？
I had that yesterday.
昨天才吃过
Get off!
省省吧！
I won't let you die before I get the money.
我一天没有收到钱，也不会让你死
How many shots do you think you need to kill me instantly, painlessly?
你觉得你要开几枪才能让我死痛快点
Don't shoot at my head, my face?
能不能不打头
You really love your look.
l｝白死还这样爱美
Anyway, until the neighbor smell the stink,
只不过，等邻居闻到臭味
and the police come in,
警察敲门进来
maybe worms are already all over my body.
说不定我已经满身爬满了尸虫
I won't be good looking by then.
那能好看呢？
Forget it...
算了…
Okay, I'll let the police ompete with the worms, is that all right?
我第一时间让警察跟尸虫斗快行了吧？
He has wired the money.
他已经转账了
Do you think you can still spend the money
这样，你还觉得自己有命花这笔钱
You never know before trying.
不试过又怎么知道
From this oracle,
这是明夷卦，明夷利艰贞
The first part means the land, the second part means the sun.
上卦坤是地，下卦离是太阳
The sun's down the land becomes dark, it means difficulties.
太阳沉于地下，光明受损，处境艰难
So you have to be patient and keep your faith.
唯有刻苦忍耐，坚守正道
Wait and get prepared, so you'll get it over.
韬光养晦以自保才会有利
Mr. Yiu, the police called, saying that they found a body.
饶先生，警察局来电话说找到一具尸体
They want you to identify if it's young master.
想你去看一下是不是夏少爷？
You said I'd face some difficulties.
你刚才说处境艰难
Does it mean my son...?
是不是说我儿子…？
It's an emperor story.
明夷于南狩，得其大首，不可疾贞
At the ancient time, the General was locked up.
周文王被封王囚禁
At last, he took a rebellion...
最后采取行动…
He toppled the reign of a tyrant.
推翻暴君
I dreamed of a coffin, my husband was sleeping inside.
我梦见我老公睡在棺材里
People around dragged me away.
周围的人拉开我
Suddenly, my husband sat up and told me that.
我老公突然坐起来跟我说
He wanted to have lunch with me.
他想跟我吃午餐
People sometimes see relatives leaving them in their dreams.
人有时候都会梦见亲人离开自己的情景
Your husband is in a mood again lately.
你老公最近情绪又很不稳定
He got many tough cases.
他接到很多麻烦的工作
Men are always not willing to admit they have emotional problems.
很多男人都不肯承认自己的情绪有问题
He likes his job.
他很喜欢他的工作
At the same time, he hates it.
同时也很讨厌
It's because he has to help someone who doesn't deserve it.
因为他要帮一些根本不值得帮的人
Or, he shouldn't measure who deserve it or not.
或许他不应该再计较谁值得帮谁不值
I know and my husband knows it too.
我明白，我老公也很明白
Actually he knows they're guilty.
其实他也知道他们有罪
So, he finds it very painful to keep working. He feels confused.
所以他一直都觉得很辛苦，很矛盾
If you were him, what would you do?
如果是你，你会怎样做？
Since the fingure and the age of this victim
因为身材、年龄
is similar to the descriptions of your son,
和你儿子很相似
Mr. Yiu, please.
饶先生，请你认一下
Mr. Yiu, are you okay?
饶先生，你没事吧？
I can't find a single thing that looks like our young master,
那死人跟少爷没一处相像
are you just fooling?
你耍我们
Mind your words.
你不要乱说话
Now, sign and leave.
如果不是就出去签名走罢
Find Boss Jim for me, I want to talk to him.
帮我找权叔，我要和他谈谈
Yes, Mr. Yiu.
知道了，饶先生
Give me back my son!...
把儿子还给我…
Hurry up!
快点！
Give my son back to me!
把儿子还给我！
What are you doing? No!
做什么呀…
My son...
我儿子…
Your son died more terribly than you are going to be.
你的儿子死得比你惨很多
Good! That's called doing justice to the world!
好呀，这样就叫做替天行道
It's not easy to kill Yiu Tin-chung.
要杀饶天颂可不是这么容易
But, you hate him so much, killing him can't satisfy you, right!
何况你憎I限到杀了他也不够
So you stole the person he loved.
所以捉了他最痛爱的人
and make him so anxious to do something stupid, finally killing himself.
让他的心急如焚，然后自寻死路
Every time you kill, have you thought about the consequences?
你每一次杀人之前，有没有想过后果
Do you get something wrong in here?
你的脑袋是不是有问题
I am a nice guy.
我是一个好人
I am a good attorney.
我是一个好律师
You need to support your case by evidences.
法律是讲究证据
You have no witness, so I'll win. I know the laws.
你们不够证据，所以我打赢了
All because of you trash.
就是因为你们这班废物
I just helped you to clean up the mess.
所以我才帮你清理这些垃圾
Have you thought of your family?
你有没有想过你身边的人？
Have you thought that you have done something bad to her?
你有没有想过对得起她吗？
You follow me everyday. You can see that.
你每天跟着我，你看见我
You know I am a nice guy.
你知道我是好人
I follow her everyday.
我天天跟着她
She is not happy, do you know that?
她很不开心，你知不知道？
You are so weak.
你也是垃圾
Stupid ass, why didn't you kill all those bastards?
废物，为什么不杀光这些人？
If you can't do it, let me do it for you.
你没本事就让我来
Let me do justice to the world.
让我主持公道
Why did you lock her up?
你为什么要困住她？
She is sad, do you know that?
她很不开心你知不知道？
NO!
不要呀！
Let him go!
你放开他！
Fong!
素芳！
He killed many people!
他杀了很多人！
He will hurt you.
他会害你
I beg you to let him go!
我求你放了他！
You will kill him!
你这样他会死！
We can be together soon.
我们很快就可以在一起
I've found you for ten years.
我找你已经十年
I have also found you for these ten years.
我也找了你十年
I've been waiting for you.
我一直都在等着你
I feel so bad.
我也很辛苦
Hubby!
老公！
Don't come over!
你不要过来！
On that day, I squatted down to avoid that shot,
那天我避开那枪
just because I suddenly thought of you.
因为我突然间想起你
You are the last woman that I should trust in this planet.
你是世界上最不能相信的女人
I am really so bad
我为人这么差
If you have chance, you'll kill me for sure.
有机会你肯定会再杀我
Two erinaceous sheltered from rain together.
两只箭猪在外躲雨
You saw it yourself or you just heard that story?
你是见过还是听过
What if one erinaceous and one crocodile,
一只箭猪，一条鳄鱼
do you think they can make it?
你说行不行？
It depends on how long the rain lasts.
那就要看这雨下多久了
Is your real name Ting?
你真名是叫阿定吗？
What?
怎么了？
Ting is a nice name.
阿定这名字不错
We got the lab report.
化验报告出来了
The skin tissue in So Fu-on's nails,
苏富安手指甲里面的皮肤屑
matches the DNA of T o.
证实了和杜厚生的ONA是一样
So, To Hou-sang admitted that,
所以杜厚生承认
he killed So Fu-on during the time he suffered from a mental disorder.
他在精神错乱的状态去杀人
How about Yiu's son?
饶天颂的儿子？
He said nothing regarding him.
他没有说
We still can't find the body.
又找不到尸体
We have a vacancy here.
我这里有空位
Why don't you apply for a transfer to here?
不如申请调过来
I've found a better place.
我找到地方落脚了
Really? Where?
是吗？去哪里？
I'll take up Uncle Choi's duty.
接才叔的职位
For the Missing Person Unit? It's a boring job.
人口失踪？很闷的
You have to go to the morgue all the time.
一去就要去硷房
Not exactly.
也不是
Finally, someone missing would be found.
总有人能寻回的
Finish her off!
把她干掉！
Do it!
动手！
This is the first time!
你总有第一次！